Guide to the Dori Laub Interviews of Holocaust Survivors
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Dori Laub interviews of Holocaust survivors
2002-2003
MS 1986
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.94
(40 boxes)
The collection consists of video recordings and transcripts of interviews conducted with Holocaust survivors by Dori Laub, psychoanalyst and psychiatrist, Holocaust survivor, and co-founder of the Fortunoff Video Archive of Holocaust Testimonies.
Laub, Dori, 1937-
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of interviews conducted by Dr. Dori Laub, of Holocaust survivors who were psychiatric patients at the Beer Yaakov Hospital in Israel. Included are video recordings of each interview in the native language of each interviewee, a one-page index of interviews, and transcriptions in English for most of the interviews. Some of the interviews were recorded using both PAL and NTSC standards.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged alphabetically.
Biographical / Historical
Dori Laub was born in Czernowitz, Romania, in 1937. A survivor of the Nazi Holocaust, Laub emigrated to Israel in 1950 where he attended medical school. Dr. Laub became a psychiatrist and psychoanalyst, emigrated to the United States, and settled in New Haven, Connecticut, where he was an affiliate of Yale New Haven Hospital. Beginning in 1979, Dr. Laub collaborated with Laurel Vlock to videotape Holocaust survivor testimony, which led to the founding of the Holocaust Survivors Film Project and subsequently the Fortunoff Video Archive for Holocaust Testimonies. Laub died on June 23, 2018, in Woodbridge, Connecticut.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Dori Laub, 2012.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Holocaust survivors; Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945) -- Personal narratives; World War, 1939-1945; Laub, Dori, 1937-
- Index of interviews, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Ben Meir, Shmuel (Blumpshpol)
  - Video recordings, 4
    Conditions Governing Access
    Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
    - Tape 1A [PAL], 2003 April 27 (Box 2)
    - Tape 2A [PAL], 2003 April 27 (Box 3)
    - Tape 10A [PAL], 2003 April 28 (Box 4)
    - Tape 11A PAL], 2003 April 28 (Box 5)
  - Transcript, 2003 April 27 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Berger, Eliahu, video recording, 2
  - Tape 11 [NTSC], 2002 November 26 (Box 6)
  - Tape 11[PAL], 2002 November 26 (Box 7)
- Brukshtein, Ida, 1
  - Video recording, Tape 6A [PAL], 2003 April 27; 1 (Box 8)
- Druker, Yitzhak
  - Video recording, Tape 9 [NTSC], 2002 November 25; 1 (Box 9)
- Flentzer, Shalom
  - Video recordings, 5
    - Tape 2 [NTSC], 2002 November 24 (Box 10)
    - Tape 2 [PAL], 2002 November 24 (Box 11)
    - Tape 3 [NTSC], 2002 November 24 (Box 12)
    - Tape 3 [PAL], 2002 November 24 (Box 13)
    - Tape 11A [PAL], 2003 April 28 (Box 5)
  - Transcript, 2002 November 24 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Fridman, Rachel
  - Video recordings, 4
    - Tape 11 [NTSC], 2002 November 26 (Box 6)
    - Tape 11 [PAL], 2002 November 26 (Box 7)
    - Tape 12 [NTSC], 2002 November 26 (Box 14)
    - Tape 12 [PAL], 2002 November 26 (Box 15)
  - Transcript, 2002 November 26 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Goldstein, Binyamin
  - Video recordings, 5
    - Tape 15 [NTSC], 2002 November 26-27 (Box 16)
    - Tape 15 [PAL], 2002 November 26-27 (Box 17)
    - Tape 16 [NTSC], 2002 November 27 (Box 18)
    - Tape 16 [PAL], 2002 November 27 (Box 19)
    - Tape 11A [PAL], 2003 April 28 (Box 5)
  - Transcript, 2002 November 27 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Grienberg, Pinchas
  - Video recording, Tape 7A [PAL], 2003 April 27; 1 (Box 20)
  - Transcript, 2003 April 27 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Heller, Avraham
  - Video recording, Tape 4A [PAL], 2003 April 27; 1 (Box 21)
  - Transcript, 2003 April 27 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Rittberg, Tilli, 1
  - Video recording, Tape 8A [PAL], 2003 April 27; 1 (Box 22)
- Rodomosky, Halina, video recordings, 3
  - Tape 9 [NTSC], 2002 November 25 (Box 9)
  - Tape 10 [NTSC], 2002 November 26 (Box 23)
  - Tape 10 [PAL], 2002 November 26 (Box 24)
- Rokovsky, Rafi
  - Video recordings, 4
    - Tape 19 [NTSC], 2002 November 28 (Box 25)
    - Tape 19 [PAL], 2002 November 28 (Box 26)
    - Tape 20 [NTSC], 2002 November 28 (Box 27)
    - Tape 20 [PAL], 2002 November 28 (Box 28)
  - Transcript, 2002 November 28 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Rosenfeld, Oranka
  - Video recordings, 4
    - Tape 14 [NTSC], 2002 November 26 (Box 29)
    - Tape 14 [PAL], 2002 November 26 (Box 30)
    - Tape 15 [NTSC], 2002 November 26-27 (Box 16)
    - Tape 15 [PAL], 2002 November 26-27 (Box 17)
  - Transcript, 2002 November 26 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Siass, Rachel (Sayas)
  - Video recordings, 5
    - Tape 1 [NTSC], 2002 November 24 (Box 31)
    - Tape 1 [PAL], 2002 November 24 (Box 32)
    - Tape 2 [NTSC], 2002 November 24 (Box 10)
    - Tape 2 [PAL], 2002 November 24 (Box 11)
    - Tape 10A [PAL], 2003 April 28 (Box 4)
  - Transcript, 2002 November 24 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Struhl, Dina
  - Video recording, Tape 5A [PAL], 2003 April 27; 1 (Box 33)
  - Transcript, 2003 April 27 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Vladislav, Biro
  - Video recording, 5
    - Tape 13 [NTSC], 2002 November 26 (Box 34)
    - Tape 13 [PAL], 2002 November 26 (Box 35)
    - Tape 14 [NTSC], 2002 November 26 (Box 29)
    - Tape 14 [PAL], 2002 November 26 (Box 30)
    - Tape 10A [PAL], 2003 April 28 (Box 4)
  - Transcript, 2002 November 26 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Weiss, Lea Morgan
  - Video recording, Tape 3A [PAL], 2003 April 27; 1 (Box 36)
  - Transcript, 2003 April 27 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Weissman, Avraham
  - Video recordings, 4
    - Tape 16 [NTSC], 2002 November 27 (Box 18)
    - Tape 16 [PAL], 2002 November 27 (Box 19)
    - Tape 17 [NTSC], 2002 November 27 (Box 37)
    - Tape 17 [PAL], 2002 November 27 (Box 38)
  - Transcript, 2002 November 27 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Yudovitz, Alvira
  - Video recordings, 3
    - Tape 4 [NTSC], 2002 November 24 (Box 39)
    - Tape 4 [PAL], 2002 November 24 (Box 40)
    - Tape 10A [PAL], 2003 April 28 (Box 4)
  - Transcript, 2002 November 24 (Box 1, Folder 15)